<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Perl on Tina&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://perlpunk.github.io/tags/perl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Perl on Tina&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 21:18:03 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://perlpunk.github.io/tags/perl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Perl CPAN Modules Are Updated in SUSE</title>
      <link>https://perlpunk.github.io/posts/2024-04-how-suse-cpan-modules-are-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 21:18:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://perlpunk.github.io/posts/2024-04-how-suse-cpan-modules-are-updated/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Packages for SUSE distributions are built in the Open Build Service (OBS).&#xA;In my previous posts I showed how a perl module is built in OBS and how you can use it as a CI.&#xA;Now I want to show how we at SUSE maintain modules that are part of an official openSUSE release.&#xA;In the devel:languages:perl repository we currently have over 3100 perl modules from CPAN.&#xA;Not all of them land in the official SUSE distribution repositories though.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using OBS as a CI for Perl Modules</title>
      <link>https://perlpunk.github.io/posts/2024-04-obs-as-a-ci-for-perl-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 23:11:55 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://perlpunk.github.io/posts/2024-04-obs-as-a-ci-for-perl-modules/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In my previous Building a Perl Module in OBS post I showed how you can build rpm packages in OBS from your perl module(s). Every commit on the main branch will trigger a new build.&#xA;Now I will show how to automatically build the package from a GitHub Pull Request. It&amp;rsquo;s recommended to read the previous post first.&#xA;For that I need to add an OBS Workflow. I need a GitHub Token, an OBS Token and a workflow YAML file.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Perl Module in OBS</title>
      <link>https://perlpunk.github.io/posts/2024-04-building-a-perl-module-in-obs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 20:45:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://perlpunk.github.io/posts/2024-04-building-a-perl-module-in-obs/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The Open Build Service is used to build all packages for the SUSE operating system family. It can also be used to build other package formats.&#xA;In this post I want to show you how you can setup a project to build your perl module(s) in OBS. Some parts might not be that intuitive, so I documented everything with screenshots.&#xA;In my next post I will show how you can setup your package to automatically build on pull requests.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
